Nelson Ewelike

Software Developer

No 36 alabi oyo Akoka, Lagos State 08143291888 emekaewelike@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Nelson Ewelike is a well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. I handle any part of the process with ease. I am also a collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 3+ years of related experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS, JAVASCRIPT, C#, REACTJS, VUEJS, DOTNET, SASS, TAILWIND CSS. SQL. NOSQL

OTHER SKILLS

CRITICAL THINKING, PROBLEM SOLVING, DEVELOPER COLLABORATION, CULTURAL AWARENESS, AGILE FRAMEWORK

EXPERIENCE

Infinion Technologies, Victoria Island, Lagos - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

- Organized workshops for .Net Modernization and migrations from local data storage to azure cloud platform.
- Implemented single and multiple tenant applications with AzureAD.
- Implemented front and Backend solutions using reactjs and Aspnetcore as my build tool.
- refactored company code base to increase readability and scalability.
- Developed clear specifications for project plans using customer requirements.

Mentored interns and delivered training to boost team skills set.

The Bulb Africa, Jibowu, Lagos - C# Developer

JANUARY 2022 - AUGUST 2022

- developed, designed, tested and maintained mobile and web applications
- worked hand in hand with the Devops team in Containerizing and shipping javascript and c# applications
- took part in requirement gatherings and creating PRDs for new applications needed by the organization
- created frontend solutions at times when company was short sta
 ed
- Used interpersonal and communication skills in interactions, enriching team collaboration, customer relationships on multiple projects.

Astutia Technologies, Illupeju - Frontend Developer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

- Advocated for well-tested and documented, high quality code.
- Made recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment to business goals.
- Worked cooperatively with client services, sales and design team in deadline-driven environment.
- Transformed native applications into mobile-friendly products.
- Teamed on user-centric design strategy in translation of UX and business requirements into coded solutions.
- Coded using HTML, CSS and JavaScript with Frameworks like REACJS and VUEJS to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.

EDUCATION

Techstudio Academy, Onikpanu, Lagos State - B.TECH

JAN 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Fullstack Software Development.

FUTA, Akure, Ondo State - B.TECH

JAN 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2017

Computer Science.

WORK SOCIALS

Github - https://github.com/nelliejellie

Linked IN-https://www.linkedin.com/in/nelson-ewelike-O1aOa6186/

Portfolio - http://emekaewelike.herokuapp.com/